Gilang Gumilar

Software Engineer

15339, Jakarta Metropolitan Area, ID

I have more than two years of demonstrated experience working as a software engineer at two unicorn startup companies based in Indonesia. I consider myself to be a life-long learner. I like to code and solve algorithmic problems with it.

SKILLS

Frontend

vue.js | vuex | nuxt.js | reactjs | redux | next.js | node.js | express.js | jest | typescript

Backend

python | java | ruby on rails | sql | django | django rest framework | flask | postgresql

DevOps

docker | kubernetes | aws | terraform | gitlab ci/cd | gcp | kops (kubernetes operations)

Others

git | c++ | webgl | machine learning

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer at Traveloka

https://www.traveloka.com/

June 2019- Current

Traveloka is an Indonesian unicorn company that provides airline ticketing, hotel booking services, and lifestyle products. I work as a full-stack engineer building Axes for Biz which is a public self-onboard platform of Traveloka Xperience products.

- Maintain and implement UI forms. (ReactJS, Next.js)
- Improve the landing page performance (Lighthouse audit) by 154%. (ReactJS, Chrome DevTools)
- Design and implement database models and backend services. (PostgreSQL, Java)
- Implement a CI/CD of the static web frontend. (AWS, Terraform, Next.js)
- Research and Implement a serverless stack. (AWS, Serverless Framework)

Part-time Frontend Engineer at Bukalapak

March 2018- May 2019

https://www.bukalapak.com/

Bukalapak is an Indonesian unicorn company and one of the leading online marketplaces in Indonesia. I worked as a part-time frontend engineer at Core Frontend team.

- Implemented an internal dashboard of Core Trust and Safety team. (Vue.js, VueX, Vuetify, Express.js)
- Implemented a Vue UI Component Library. (Vue.js, Storybook, Jest, SASS)

Part-time Full-stack Engineer at GoriTax

January 2019- April 2019

https://www.goritax.com/

GoriTax is a curated tax and accounting experts as a service.

- Designed the database (SQL, PostgreSQL), created the backend with a RESTful API (Python, Django, Django REST framework), and created the server infrastructure (Docker, Kubernetes, AWS, Kops, Gitlab CI/CD).
- Implemented the frontend with a frontend engineer. (ReactJS, Redux, Material-UI)

Frontend Engineer Intern at Bukalapak

December 2017- March 2018

https://www.bukalapak.com/

Bukalapak is an Indonesian unicorn company and one of the leading online marketplaces in Indonesia.

Rewrote the product detail page on the mobile web using Vue.js and RESTful API. (Vue.js, VueX, Nuxt.js)

Teaching Assistant at Computer Science Faculty of Universitas Indonesia https://www.cs.ui.ac.id/

September 2017- December 2017

Assisted the lecturer of Web Design and Programming (International Class) course.

- Assisted students in lab sessions.
- Created weekly lab tutorials with other assistants.

Web Developer Intern at Jojonomic

January 2017- February 2017

https://jojonomic.com/

Jojonomic provides services that can easily control company expenses with Real-Time Approval.

Developed web app features using HTML, CSS, JS.

	\sim	 		_	_	_	_
W	m		N		_	-	н

Community Contributor at GitLab

March 2020 - Current

GitLab is an open source web-based DevOps lifecycle tool. I contribute to GitLab by fixing and implementing several features.

■ The second most MRs merged (57 MRs merged) of GitLab Hackathon Q2'2020. (Vue.js, Ruby on Rails)

Math Tutor at Computer Science Faculty's Student Council of Universitas Indonesia

April 2016 - May 2016

BETIS (Bimbingan Belajar Gratis) is a free tutoring program from Computer Science Faculty's Student Council for high school students or equivalent to prepare the national college entrance examination (SBMPTN).

Helped students solved math problems.

AWARDS

Frontend Development Certification at freeCodeCamp

2016

Achieved "Frontend Development Certification" from freeCodeCamp at https://www.freeCodeCamp.org/gilangmlr. Created several projects to achieve the certification which hosted at https://codepen.io/gilangmlr

EDUCATION

LANGUAGES

Bachelor Computer Science at Universitas Indonesia **2015 - 2019**

EnglishProfessional working proficiency

Indonesian
Native proficiency